Guide to the A. Poulin Papers and BOA Editions Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
A. Poulin papers and BOA Editions records
1951-1996
YCAL MSS 635
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
136.34
(134 boxes)
The A. Poulin Papers and BOA Editions Records provide evidence of the personal and professional life of American poet A. Poulin and the publishing company he founded, BOA Editions. The papers document Poulin's career as a poet, editor, translator, and publisher and consist of correspondence, manuscripts, books, business papers, photographs, videotapes, computer disks, and printed material concerning BOA Editions. Correspondents include Graywolf Press, Lucille Clifton, Anne He?bert, David Ignatow, Li-Young Lee, John Logan, Peter Makuck, Bertrand Mathieu, Anthony Piccione, Katerina Angelake?-Rouk, Louis Simpson, and W. D. Snodgrass, among others. The archive provides evidence of the founding and early work of BOA Editions and sheds light into the American not-for-profit publishing industry in the later twentieth-century.
Poulin, A., Jr., 1938-1996
BOA Editions
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from James S. Jaffe on the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund and Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 1988, 1993, and 1997.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 9, 38-39, 79, 83, 111, 126, 133, and 134 (audiovisual materials): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Boxes 37 and 84 (reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 132 (computer disks): Original computer disks are restricted. Copies of electronic files are available through Access Services.
A. Poulin (1938-1996)
Al Poulin, American poet, editor, translator, and publisher, was born in Lisbon, Maine in 1938.
Poulin attended St. Francis College in Maine where he received a B.A. in 1960. He continued his studies in literature at Loyola University in Chicago, where he earned an M.A. in 1960. Poulin attended the University of Iowa between 1966 and 1968 ultimately obtaining an M.F.A. in poetry (his thesis was In Advent: Poems and Translations ).
Poulin taught literature for a number of years, with stints at Loyola University (1960-1962), St. Francis College (1962-1964; 1968-1971), the University of Maryland (1965), and the University of New Hampshire (1965-1966). In 1971 Poulin became a Professor of English at the State University of New York at Brockport, a position he held until poor health forced his retirement.
In 1976 Poulin founded BOA Editions, an independent, non-profit literary publishing company specializing in American poetry and poetry-in-translation. Poulin appealed to his friend and colleague W. D. Snodgrass for a manuscript for BOA's first project, which resulted in The Führer Bunker: A Cycle of Poems in Progress.
Poulin's poetry publications include In Advent (1972), Catawba: Omens, Prayers & Songs (1977), Widow's Taboo: Poems After the Catawba (1977), Nameless Garden (1978), Nest of Sonnets (1985), Momentary Order (1987), Cave Dwellers (1991), and Angels (1994).
He also published translations of the poetry of Rainer Maria Rilke and Anne He?bert. In 1972 Poulin began editing Contemporary American Poetry, an anthology published by Houghton Mifflin.
Poulin was married to Basilike H. Parkas, with whom he had one daughter (Daphne). Poulin later married Elizabeth ("Boo") Poulin who he met in 1963 when teaching at the University of New Hampshire.
Poulin died at the age of fifty-eight in Brockport, New York, on June 5, 1996 of complications related to pulmonary disorders.
Scope and Contents
The A. Poulin Papers and BOA Editions Records provide evidence of the personal and professional life of American poet A. Poulin and the publishing company he founded, BOA Editions. The papers document Poulin's career as a poet, editor, translator, and publisher and consist of correspondence, manuscripts, books, business papers, photographs, audiovisual material, computer disks, and printed material concerning BOA Editions. The archive provides evidence of the founding and early work of BOA Editions and sheds light into the American not-for-profit publishing industry in the later twentieth-century.
Poulin's creative life is reflected in his writings and correspondence. The papers include various drafts of his poetry and other writing projects, such as Contemporary American Poetry. Poulin's correspondence reflects his literary circle and work with BOA Editions, with correspondents including publisher Graywolf Press, and writers Lucille Clifton, Anne Hébert, David Ignatow, Li-Young Lee, John Logan, Peter Makuck, Bertrand Mathieu, Anthony Piccione, Katerina Anghelaki-Rooke, Louis Simpson, and W. D. Snodgrass, among others.
Poulin's personal life is recorded in his correspondence with his wife Elizabeth ("Boo") Poulin and friends.
Arrangement
Organized into three groupings: I. July 1988 Acquisition, 1956-1986. II. September 1993 Acquisition, 1960-1991. III. May 1997 Acquisition, 1951-1996.
Material within this collection has been organized by acquisition reflecting the fact that the collection has been acquired in increments over time. Researchers should note that material within each acquisition overlaps with/or relates to material found in other acquisitions. For instance, correspondence and writings can be found in all three groupings. In order to locate all relevant material within this collection, researchers will need to consult each acquisition described in the Collection Contents section.
Researchers should also note that similar material can be arranged differently in each acquisition, depending on how the material was organized when it was received by the library.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors and publishers -- United States; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Literature publishing -- United States; Poets, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Publishers and publishing -- United States; Small presses -- United States; Born digital; Audiovisual materials; Sound recordings; Audiocassettes; Videocassettes; Angelakē-Rouk, Katerina, 1939-; Clifton, Lucille, 1936-2010; Hébert, Anne, 1916-2000; Ignatow, David, 1914-1997; Lee, Li-Young, 1957-; Logan, John, 1923-1987; Makuck, Peter, 1940-; Mathieu, Bertrand, 1936-; Piccione, Anthony, 1939-2001; Poulin, A., Jr., 1938-1996; Simpson, Louis, 1923-2012; Snodgrass, W. D. (William De Witt), 1926-2009; BOA Editions; Graywolf Press
- July 1988 Acquisition, 1956-1986; 1; 44.33; (39 boxes)
  Arrangement
  This group of material is organized into two subgroups: Correspondence and Manuscripts, and Audiovisual Material.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 37 (reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 9, 38-39 (audio cassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Scope and Contents
  Personal and professional papers of Al Poulin and BOA Editions archives.
  General note
  Former call number: Uncat ZA MS 69.
  - Correspondence and Manuscripts
    - Bertrand, Mathieu
      - Essay on Henry Miller, 1984 (Box 1)
      - "The Charioteer," translation of Jacques Lacarrière's "L'Aurige", 1984 (Box 1)
      - Kenneth White essay, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Snodgrass, W. D.: "The Führer Bunker," with related correspondence, 5 (Box 1)
    - Stafford, William: Poetry published in "Things That Happen Where There Aren't Any People" (Box 1)
    - Stroud, Joseph: "Signatures," with related correspondence, 3 (Box 1)
    - Sutter, Barton: "Cedarhome," forward by W. D. Snodgrass, with related correspondence, 3 (Box 1)
    - Wallenstein, Barry: "Beast Is a Wolf with Brown Fire," forward by M. L. Rosenthal, with related and correspondence, 3 (Box 1)
    - Walters, Michael: "Not Just Any Death" (Box 1)
    - Wendt, Ingrid: "Moving the House," forward by W. D. Snodgrass (Box 1)
    - Whitbread, Thomas: "Whomp and Moonshiver," forward by Richard Wilbur (Box 1)
    - Wilbur, Richard: "The Whale and Other Uncollected Translations" (Box 1)
    - Amorosi, Ray: correspondence (includes some manuscripts), 1973-1975 (Box 2)
    - Berrigan, David: correspondence and photographs, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Bly, Robert: correspondence and photographs, 1967-1974 (Box 2)
    - Bishop, Elizabeth: correspondence and photographs, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Carver, Leslie: correspondence, 1957-1958 (Box 2)
    - Creeley, Robert: correspondence and photographs, 1967-1972 (Box 2)
    - Dickey, James: correspondence and photographs, 1969-1973 (Box 2)
    - Hall, Donald: correspondence, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Heyen, William: correspondence and clippings, 1970-1973 (Box 2)
    - Hoffman, Daniel: correspondence, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Howard, Richard: correspondence, circa 1974 (Box 2)
    - Hugo, Richard: correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 2)
    - Ignatow, David: correspondence and photographs, 1973-1976 (Box 2)
    - Jacobsen, Josephine: correspondence, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Kinnell, Galway: correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 2)
    - Kizer, Carolyn: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Koch, Kenneth: correspondence, 1969 (Box 2)
    - Kumin, Maxine: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Kunitz, Stanley: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Malanga, Gerard: correspondence and clippings, circa 1975; 2 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence regarding the Negro and American Quest for Identity Symposium, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
      Includes A. P. Randolph, J. H. Reed, R. McGill, Martin E. Marty, C. Mathias, J. C. Murray, J. Lewis, H. Stuard Hughes, J. Forman, J. Doar, R. Drinan, N. Cousins, H. Commager, T. Cornell, P. Cuneo, A. Chalmers, R. MacAfee Brown, B. Bettelheum, G. Baum, C. Vann Woodward, A. C. Powell, N. Podhoretz, P. Scharper, R. Shinn, B. Rustin, Father M. Louis (Thomas Merton), Lippman, R. Gay, G. Diekmann, J. Cunneen, J. Coles, P. Chapman, G. Davis, J. Burns, T. Walsh, G. Weigel, D. Thorman, S. Tupper, C. Phillips, R. W. Cromey, S. Carmichael, E. Muskie, M. L. King, L. Fiedler, L. Happersberger, R. Howes, J. O'Gara, D. Feeney, K. Stern.
    - Correspondence regarding NYSCA (New York State Council on the Arts), 1977-1981 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence regarding Younger Poets (includes some manuscripts), 1967-1972; 3 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence regarding a symposium to be held in September 1973, 1958-1976 (Box 2)
      Includes P. Rahv, B. Roethke, J. Kosinski, M. Geismar, S. Stephanchev, D. Wakoski, D. Ignatow, D. Autin, W. Packard, J. M. Brinnin, P. Booth, G. Keithley, M. L. Rosenthal, P. Klappert, J. Tate, G. Corso, C. Kizer, L. Lieberman, M. Heller, S. Plumly, M. Benedikt, F. Lima, D. Hoffman, A. Porter, S. Berg, S. Mooney, C. Van Doren, S. Spander, J. Ciardi, N. Mailer, M. McCarthy, H. Rago, L. Fiedler, J. Jacobson, G. Kinnell, W. Matthews.
    - Miscellaneous correspondence regarding an unnamed anthology, circa 1975 (Box 2)
      Includes W. Chaplin, J. Stroud, P. Simpson, Cynthia NB, L. Simpson, M. Piercy, M. McLure, J. Tate.
    - Proposals for books (Box 2)
    - Surveys regarding Rilke book, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
      Includes Howard, Rosenthal, Kunitz, Logan, Schevill, MacLeish, Moss, Scully, Stryk, Leventov, Snodgrass, Ciardi, Kinnell, Ferlinghetti, Oates, Wilbur, Brinnin, Hall, Eberhart, Dugan, Meredith, Creeley, Bly, Warren, Dickey, Kennedy, Bishop, Wagover, Stafford, Rothenbert, Ignatow.
    - Rich, Adrienne: correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
    - Simpson, Louis: correspondence, photographs, and manuscripts (signed), 1967-1974 (Box 2)
    - Snodgrass, W. D.: correspondence, 1967-1973 (Box 2)
    - Snyder, Gary: correspondence and photographs, circa 1973 (Box 2)
    - Stafford, William: correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 2)
    - Stryk, Lucien: correspondence, 1972-1976 (Box 2)
    - Tate, Allen: correspondence, 1974 (Box 2)
    - Vendler, Helen: correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 2)
    - Warren, Robert Penn: correspondence, 1973 (Box 2)
    - Waters, Michael: correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 2)
    - Wilbur, Richard: correspondence and photographs, 1969-1974 (Box 2)
    - Wright, James: correspondence and photographs, 1969-1970 (Box 2)
    - BOA Editions
      - Correspondence
        - Board of Advisors, 1978 June-July; 2 (Box 3)
        - NYSCA, general (Box 3)
        - Poets interested in cooperative (Box 3)
        - Responses from editors and bookstores (Box 3)
        - Responses from professionals (regarding prospectus) (Box 3)
        - Other publishers (Box 3)
      - Early prospectus (Box 3)
      - Financial statements, 1978-1981; 3 (Box 3)
      - Invoices, 1977-1982; 2 (Box 3)
      - Ledger: checking account, 1978-1979 (Box 3)
      - Lists of review copies sent out (regarding Snodgrass' The Führer Bunker and Sutter's Cedarhome, etc.) (Box 3)
      - List of reviewers and individuals to receive complimentary copies (Box 3)
      - Promotion: Daniela Gioseffi (Box 3)
      - Prospectus (Box 3)
      - Receptions (Box 3)
      - Rejections, 1977-1982; 9 (Box 3)
      - Summary prospectus (Box 3)
    - BOA Incorporation: correspondence and related documents (Box 3)
    - Poulin, Al
      - Awards correspondence and miscellaneous (Box 3)
      - Correspondence regarding Gotham Reception, City College of New York, circa 1978 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence regarding Liftbridge Party, April 1975, circa 1975 (Box 3)
      - Correspondence regarding Panel on Alternative Publishers - National Book Awards Week (Box 3)
      - Correspondence regarding Visual Studies Workshop and miscellaneous (Box 3)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1978 September (Box 3)
        Includes correspondence regarding COSMEP, Kruchkow, et. al., NYSCA.
      - Panel on Alternative Publishers - National Book Awards Week (Box 3)
    - Bell, Marvin: "The Escape Into You" (Box 4)
    - Berg, Stephen: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Co., Inc: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Carroll, Paul: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Dacey, Philip: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Haas, Robert: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Harper, Michael: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Heyen, William: "Noise in the Trees: Poems of Long Island," manuscript signed with inscription (Box 4)
    - Houghton-Mifflin Company: correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 4)
    - Klappert, Peter: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Knoepfle, John: manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Kuzma, Greg: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Lux, Thomas: manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Orr, Gregory: manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Poulin, Al
      - Correspondence regarding Poulin's translations of Anne Hébert's poetry (Box 4)
      - Correspondence regarding readings, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
      - Correspondence regarding Spring 1973 Poetry Symposium, 1972-1973; 2 (Box 4)
      - Manuscripts, 1971 November - 1972 May; 3 (Box 4)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1968-1980; 8 (Box 4)
      - Translation of works by Gatien Lapointe (Box 4)
    - Oates, Joyce Carol: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Simic, Charles: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 4)
    - Simpson, Peter
      - "A Sound Departure," manuscript with inscription and cover letter (Box 4)
      - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Starbuck, George: correspondence (Box 4)
    - Ellipse: correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
    - Galassi, Jonathan: correspondence regarding Poulin's translations of Rilke's sonnets and elegies, circa 1976 (Box 5)
    - Graywolf Press: correspondence (Box 5)
    - Poulin, Al
      - American novel lectures, circa 1968-1969 (Box 5)
      - Contemporary American Poetry, revised. Prospectus and other business related documents (Box 5)
      - Contemporary American Poetry, revised, 1973. The notebooks of David Ignatow, revised, 1974, 1973-1974 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence regarding Gerber, Philip ("Gerbergate") (Box 5)
      - Correspondence regarding personal publications and rejections, 1970-1976; 3 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence regarding readings (Box 5)
      - Correspondence regarding Rilke translation, reviews, circa 1978 (Box 5)
      - Correspondence with publishers, circa 1979 (Box 5)
      - "The Elephant's Womb: A Bestiary of the Will," manuscripts, 1972; 4 (Box 5)
      - "I Belong to the Earth: Ode to the Saint Lawrence," by Gatien Lapointe, translation, 1973 May 6 (Box 5)
      - Manuscripts for reviews and essays, including some related correspondence (Box 5)
      - Miscellany found loose in box (Box 5)
      - Plath essay, 1973 (Box 5)
      - Poetry by Saint-Denys-Garneau, translated by Poulin, 1973 (Box 5)
      - Poetry, unfinished / abandoned poems, circa 1974 (Box 5)
      - Poetry, 1974 April - 1978 June; 4 (Box 5)
      - "The Duino Elegies," by Rainer Maria Rilke, translation (Box 5)
      - "The Duino Elegies," and "Sonnets to Orpheus," revisions, preface, notes, commentaries on revisions, 2 (Box 5)
      - "The Roses," and "The Windows," by Rainer Maria Rilke, translation (Box 5)
      - "The Widow's Taboo: Poems after the Catawba", 4 (Box 5)
      - Worksheets, manuscripts, abandoned poems, circa 1964-1965 (Box 5)
      - "Duino Elegies and The Sonnets to Orpheus," typescripts and proofs, circa 1976; 12 (Box 6)
      - "The American Folk Scene," by Al Poulin and David Turk, 1968; 3 (Box 6)
    - Workshop (info) (Box 6)
    - Poetry writing, Summer 1967, Iowa (Box 6)
    - International Writing Program manuscripts (Box 6)
    - Workshop poets, summer 1966-1967, 3 (Box 6)
    - Berg, Stephen: "O I'm a Human Being: Versions of Eskimo," typescript copy, signed (Box 7)
    - Evangelatos, Kostantinos: correspondence, circa 1984 (Box 7)
    - Friar, Kimon: correspondence, circa 1984 (Box 7)
    - Galassi, Jonathan: "Eugenio Montale: Xenia," typescript with reader's comments (Box 7)
    - Graywolf Press / Walker Swenson Book Typographers: correspondence (Box 7)
    - Houghton-Mifflin Company: correspondence (Box 7)
      Includes some Poulin / R. Creeley correspondence.
    - Islands and Continents: correspondence (Box 7)
    - Logan, John: correspondence and "Ballet for Ear" (Box 7)
    - MacLeish, Archibald: correspondence (Box 7)
    - Mason, David: "Looking in All the Rooms, a chapbook on progress," manuscript and correspondence (Box 7)
    - Poulin, Al
      - "The Astonishment of Origins: French Sequences," by Rainer Maria Rilke, translation (Box 7)
      - Contemporary American Poetry, unbound (Box 7)
      - Correspondence: drafts of letters to miscellaneous correspondents, 1983 November - 1984 December; 2 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence regarding miscellaneous publications, circa 1983 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence regarding Philip Gerber ("Gerbergate") (Box 7)
      - Correspondence regarding readings, circa 1983 (Box 7)
      - Grants: applications and reports, circa 1984; 2 (Box 7)
      - Manuscripts, 1984 (Box 7)
      - Medical expenses and claims, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
      - "The Migration of Powers," manuscripts with reader's notes and comments, 1983 August 25; 4 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence, circa 1984; 4 (Box 7)
      - Correspondence regarding Snodgrass, Levertal, Snyder, Wilbur, Mathieu, and Lowell (Box 7)
      - Notebook, manuscript pages ripped from spiral, circa 1971-1972 (Box 7)
      - Notes for Introduction to Poetry, miscellaneous book ideas (Box 7)
      - Notes on French Canadian Poets and miscellaneous documents (Box 7)
      - Plans and correspondence: European trips, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
      - Proposals and notes: "Modern American Poets" and "Young American Poets" (Box 7)
    - Sexton, Anne: "The Awful Rowing Toward God," typescript copy, signed (Box 7)
    - Sexton, Anne: correspondence and "The Death Notebooks," typescript copy, signed (Box 7)
    - Shapiro, David: "A Man Holding an Acoustic Panel," typescript copy, signed (Box 7)
    - SUNY/ Buffalo: correspondence regarding resumption of graduate studies at SUNY Buffalo (Box 7)
    - Anderson, John: correspondence, manuscripts and photographs (Box 8)
    - Ashbery, John: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Bell, Marvin: correspondence, circa 1971-1976 (Box 8)
    - Berg, Steve: correspondence, circa 1972-1976 (Box 8)
    - Bolduc, Marcel (Box 8)
    - Cross, Michael: manuscripts (Box 8)
    - De Turk, David and Rae: correspondence, manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Dugan, Alan: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Duncan, Robert: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Eberhart, Richard: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Engle, Paul: correspondence and vitae (Box 8)
    - Everson, William (Brother Antonius): correspondence, biographical information (Box 8)
    - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence: correspondence, photographs (Box 8)
    - Fiction International: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Fiore, Peter: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Floyd, David: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Gaulin, Michel: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Ginsberg, Allen: correspondence and photographs (Box 8)
    - Lachance, Paul: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Lapointe, Gatien: correspondence, manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Laughlin, James: correspondence (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence regarding Ezra Pound's visit to Brockport.
    - Levertov, Denise: correspondence and photographs (Box 8)
    - Makuck, Pete and Jim Hart: correspondence and manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Margolin, Michael: manuscripts (Box 8)
    - Matthews, William: correspondence, publications (Box 8)
    - Mazzaro, Jerome: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Meredith, William: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Merwin, W. S. (William Stanley): correspondence, photograph (Box 8)
    - Mills, Ralph J.: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Poulin, Al
      - Applications for grants, circa 1981 (Box 8)
      - Biographical information (Box 8)
      - Correspondence regarding "The American Folk Scene" (Box 8)
      - Correspondence regarding "Contemporary American Poetry" (Box 8)
      - Correspondence regarding Elizabeth (Mrs. Alfred / Betty / Boo) Poulin (Box 8)
      - Correspondence regarding job applications to various universities (Box 8)
      - Correspondence regarding publications, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
      - Lapointe, Gatien: translations of his poetry by Al Poulin (Box 8)
    - Powers, Dee: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Rosenau, Ruth: correspondence (Box 8)
    - St. Francis College: correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 8)
    - Stokes, Terry: correspondence, photographs, publications (Box 8)
    - Strand, Mark: correspondence, copies of manuscripts (signed) (Box 8)
    - Today (National Catholic Magazine): correspondence and manuscripts by Poulin (Box 8)
    - University of Iowa: correspondence and contracts, circa 1965-1967 (Box 8)
    - Williams, C. K.: correspondence (Box 8)
    - Anghelaki-Rooke, Katerina: "Beings and Things On Their Own," proofs (Box 9)
    - BOA Editions
      - Anghelaki-Rooke, Katerina: invitations to a poetry reading (Box 9)
      - Correspondence and manuscripts: rejections, 1985-1986; 2 (Box 9)
      - Poulin, Al: "A Nest of Sonnets," signed copies and advertising material, 2 (Box 9)
      - Review copy forms (Box 9)
    - Friar, Kimon: correspondence (Box 9)
    - Kizer, Carolyn
      - Correspondence to, from, and about, 2 (Box 9)
      - "Studs Terkel with Carolyn Kizer," interview, (audiocassette), 1985 October 31; 1 (Box 39, Item barcode 39002091395682)
        Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Makuck, Peter: correspondence, publication (Box 9)
    - Mathieu, Bertrand: "Henry Miller's Divine Comedy," corrected proofs (copy) with correspondence (Box 9)
    - Poulin, Al
      - Appointment book, 1980 (Box 9)
      - Correspondence with "BOA Poets", 1982-1985 (Box 9)
      - Correspondence regarding "Isabella Gardner: The Complete Poems," ed. A. Poulin (Box 9)
    - Simpson, Louis: correspondence (Box 9)
    - Snodgrass, W. D.
      - Correspondence, manuscripts, 2 (Box 9)